Chris Wallace: award-winning executive creative director

TWITTER

EMAIL

chriswallace7@protonmail.com

WEBSITE

PHONE 972-837-7267

Professional Summary

An Emmy-nominated design executive with over 15 years of remote leadership in creative direction and design. Distinguished track record in pioneering innovative web applications, products, and editorial experiences for high-profile tech and media organizations like Google, Microsoft, Facebook, ESPN, the Boston Globe, AMC Networks, among others. Proven proficiency in implementing blockchain and AI technologies to develop novel digital ownership solutions in the realm of art and collectibles.

Work Experience

2021-Present — Remote

CEO at UltraDAO Studios

Founded a decentralized web3 creative studio focused on digital art products and collectibles. Supervised a team of digital artists, project managers, and developers, leading the creation of Woodies, a series of 10,000 unique digital collectibles and 3D characters.

- Steered the growth of product brands from inception including ULTRAPASS, Woodies, and Twelve Days of CryptoArt
- * Generated multimillion-dollar revenue within the first six months
- * Oversaw the planting of one million trees in Sub-Saharan Africa via Trees for the Future

- Awarded "Best Environmental Initiative from an NFT project" at NFT NYC 2022
- * Executive Creative Director for multiple creative projects including Woodies Generative Characters, Woodies: Origin (animated short film), Woodies 3D, and more

2017-2021 — Remote

Vice President, Experience Design at 10up

Directed the design discipline for a global agency of 250+ staff spanning three continents and 16 countries. Orchestrated design vision, emphasizing collaboration and co-design practices.

- * Grew the design team from 5 to 20 professionals, stationed across 12 time zones
- Contributed to a near doubling of agency revenue (~95%) within four years
- Successfully diversified team composition through inclusive hiring practices
- * Expanded design services to incorporate content design, illustration, video production, and more

2009-2017 — Remote

Co-Founder/Principal Creative at Lift UX

Steered a boutique team of designers and engineers, crafting apps and websites for diverse clients such as AMC Networks, Frito-Lay, and GoDaddy.

- * Launched innovative interactive second-screen apps for acclaimed TV series, earning two Emmy nominations
- ★ Hired and managed a small team of full-time and contract designers
- * Grew website traffic for the product division to 2 million monthly visitors
- * Successfully acquired by 10up in 2017

2007-2009 — St. Louis, MO

Front-End Developer at Enterprise Rent-A-Car

Developed front-end interfaces for B2B applications and B2C websites, liaising with UX designers and back-end Java engineers to execute new applications.

- * Managed weekly deployments for enterprise.com and other customer-facing applications
- * Provided QA support for monthly release cycles

2006-2007 — Belleville, IL

Senior E-Commerce Web Designer at Network Solutions

Designed and developed front-end code for e-commerce storefronts for small businesses, maintaining stringent project timelines and adhering to client specifications.

2005-2006 — St. Louis, MO

Webmaster at St. Louis Christian College

As the primary web content owner, designed, developed, and maintained the college's online presence. During my tenure, the college witnessed a 60% growth rate, reaching full campus capacity the following year.

Selected Works

Twelve Days of CryptoArt

Link: Website

Role: Curation, Branding, Web Design, Full Stack Development

Year: 2023

Branded, curated, designed, and engineered Twelve Days of CryptoArt, a blind art collecting event exhibiting new artworks from a diverse group of artists. Engineered the full web application using modern technologies, including Sveltekit, JavaScript/TypeScript, Sass, Tailwind, Prisma, PostgreSQL, Redis.

UltraDAO

Link: Website

Role: Branding, Web Design, Full Stack Developer

Year: 2021-2023

Created the branding, design language, and website for UltraDAO, including writing all content. Engineered website using Jekyll, Sass, JavaScript, and Tailwind.

Woodies: Origin

Link: YouTube

Role: Executive Creative Direction

Year: 2022

Hired and directed an international media production company to create a Hollywood-grade animated short film, engrossing fans in the Woodies universe within a span of six months and a budget of approximately \$500,000.

California DMV Website Redesign

https://dmv.ca.gov

Role: Executive Creative Direction

Year: 2020

Led a landmark project for our agency: a comprehensive redesign of the California DMV website. Assembled and guided the design team behind this task. The revamped site was met with resounding approval from both the public and DMV staff.

Google Site Kit

Link: https://sitekit.withgoogle.comRole: Executive Creative Direction

Year: 2019

In partnership with Google, launched a WordPress plugin that integrates Google's suite of products in one location. Site Kit quickly gained adoption among website owners, thanks to a design language that strikingly represented both Google's identity and the WordPress admin environment.

10up Brand & Recruiting Videos

Links: <u>Brand Video</u>, <u>Recruiting Video</u> Role: Executive Creative Direction

Year: 2018

Pitched the idea of creating two videos for 10up: one for our potential clients and a second for potential employees to meet and learn more about us. Using our annual company meetup in Jackson Hole, Wyoming as the backdrop, we flew a video crew out for a few days to capture footage and interview clients and team members. Functioned both as an Executive Producer and Creative Director for the project.

GoDaddy Go Theme

https://www.godaddy.com/wordpress-themes

Role: Executive Creative Director

Year: 2019

Collaborated with two senior designers on a project for returning client, GoDaddy.

Developed a computational design system capable of producing an endless variety of themes, resulting in a surge in user signups and WordPress users for GoDaddy. Assisted the client and internal designers with valuable insights, critiqued design progress, and worked closely with the engineering team to ensure optimal implementation of our work.

Skills

* Creative Direction

* Design Systems

* Hiring & Personnel Management

* WordPress Design & Development

* Resource & Budget Planning

* Design Operations

* Professional Development Planning

* Design Management

* Hiring & Growth

* Visual & Brand Design

Education

Missouri State University, Springfield, MO — 2004

Attended Missouri State University (formerly Southwest Missouri State) for Graphic Design. Attended one semester, withdrew for medical reasons.

Saint Louis Christian College, Florissant, MO — 2002-2004

Attended Saint Louis Christian College with a focus on General and Biblical Studies.